冷锋 男
Leng Feng Male
军衔 中士
Rank Sergeant
岗位 狙击手
Role Sniper
因在执行任务中擅自行动
Because of his unauthorized action during a mission,
根据纪律条令
the person above shall be given a penalty of confinement,
予以行政看管
in accordance with discipline regulations.
2008年8月7日
7th August 2008
据线报
According to a tip-off,
在南疆边境某地
a criminal gang
有犯罪团伙
near the southern border
秘密进行
is running a massive operation
大规模人体带毒
smuggling drugs inside carriers' bodies.
手段残忍
Their means are cruel
影响恶劣
and this is badly effecting the population.
战区决定派遣特种部队
The authorities decided to sent a special force
与当地缉毒警方
to co-operate
展开联合行动
with the local anti-drug police
抓捕该犯罪团伙
In tracking down the criminal gang.
作战部署准备完毕
Operational preparations complete.
随时可以向目标发起攻击
Ready to attack
行动
Action.
正面强攻
Attack with frontal assault.
哥 救我啊哥
Brother. Help me, brother.
救我啊
Help me.
你们已经被包围了
You are surrounded.
里面的人听着
All people in the building,
立刻放下武器
drop your weapons now.
别开枪 别开枪
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
别开枪 我出来了
Don't shoot. I'm coming out now.
我出来了
I'm coming out.
跟我一点关系都没有
It's nothing to do with me.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
啊
Ar!
给我一辆车
Get me a car!
我现在就要一辆车
I want a car now!
退后
Back off!
这个建筑建于上世纪六十年代
This building was built in the 60s.
用来储藏危险品
It was used to keep hazardous materials.
整个建筑进行了特别加固
The whole building has been specially reinforced.
墙壁结构为钢筋混凝土
The walls are made of ferroconcrete.
摩式硬度达到8
Its Mohs hardness scale is 8.
我们这次携带的武器
The weapons of ours
无法击穿
cannot penetrate it.
而在城市反恐中
It would be a massacre
使用大口径反器材武器
if we use heavy calibre anti-materiel weapons
无异于屠杀
in an urban anti-terrorist mission,
所以我们没有携带
so we didn't carry
停止攻击
Cease fire.
叫所有人停止攻击
Everyone stop attacking.
退后
Go back!
为什么违抗命令擅自开枪
Why did you shoot without authorization?
报告首长
Sir,
战友受伤
comrades were down.
时问不容耽误
Cannot wait
你提的要求我们会考虑的
Your request is negotiable
不过你先把人质给我放了
First, release the hostage
跟我拖延时问是吧
You are trying to win more time, aren't you?
我要一辆车
I want a car.
下次遇到这种情况
If it happens again,
你还会开枪吗
will you do the same?
怎么回事
What was that?
谁开的枪
Who did that?
谁他妈开的枪
Who?
狙击手
Sniper,
没有命令不准开枪
Don't shoot without order.
信不信我一枪崩了他
I can shoot his head, right now
冷静 冷静 冷静
Calm down. Calm down. Calm down.
杀人什么感觉
What was your feeling?
我是人质啊
I'm the hostage.
怎么又他妈开枪啊
Why did you fucking shoot me again?
走火 走火
Accident, accident.
真的是走火
It was really an accident.
我他妈一枪崩了他
I can shoot his fucking head right now!
你冷静点
Calm down.
冷锋
Leng Feng,
你等着关禁闭吧
wait for your confinement!
我没有杀人的感觉
I wasn't thinking about killing people,
只有救人的感觉
but saving people,
救出战友
saving my comrades.
感觉很爽
It felt good.
你感觉很爽
Were you feeling good?
是的
Yes.
战场杀敌
Killing enemies in battle
职责所在
is my duty.
你开枪有多大把握
How confident were you with your shooting?
百分之五十
50%.
那另外百分之五十呢
What about the other 50%?
在我这里没有另外百分之五十
There was no other 50% in my case.
我赢了
I won.
好了
OK.
你可以回去了
You can go back now.
报告
Excuse me, Sir!
讲
Yes.
请问是回原部队吗
Am I going back to my old troop?
回什么原部队
What old troop?
禁闭室
Confinement room.
（东南亚某地）
"Somewhere Southeast Asia"
敏登
Min Deng,
你已经被捕了
you are under arrest
罪名是走私毒品 贩卖人口
For drug trafficking, human trafficking
走私军火和支持恐怖主义活动
weapon smuggling and aiding terrorist activities.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
但你说的一切
Anything you say
都将成为呈堂证供
can and will be used against you in a court of law.
哥
Brother,
我终于帮你干成了一件大事
Finally, I did something big for you.
你赶快给我回来
Come back. Now!
哥你看你
Brother, come on.
我说了我一定能帮成你
I was always so sure that I can help you.
武吉你快跑
Wu Ji, run!
你没准已经让中国警察给包围了
You may have already been surrounded by the Chinese Police
哥
Brother,
你别吓唬我啊
don't try to scare me.
还中国警察
What Chinese Police?
警察
Police!
哪呢
Where?
警察
Police!
警察来了
Police is here!
哥 救我啊哥
Brother, help me! Brother!
救我啊
Help me.
谁开枪啊
Who did the shooting?
我是人质
I'm the hostage.
谁开枪
Who did the shooting?
怎么对着人质开枪啊
How could you shoot at the hostage?
我弟弟是个永远长不大的孩子
My brother was just a child could never grew up.
太想证明自己了
So eager to prove himself
这才冒冒失失闯入中国
so he rashly ran into China,
想做些事情来证明给我看
trying to prove himself to me
没想到
He never thought
把命送在了中国
that he would die in China.
这个中国小子
A Chinese guy?
不要小看中国
Don't look down upon China.
当你遇到他的时候
When you meet them,
你就知道你面对的是什么
you will know what you are up against.
中国
China
那可是你们雇佣兵的禁地
That is the red zone of you mercenaries
当他们遇到我的时候
When they meet me,
他们就知道要面对的是什么
they will know what they are up against.
有人认为
Some people think
军人违抗军令
A soldier could never disobeys his order,
就应该脱了军装
other wise he should take off his uniform
滚蛋回家
and go home.
也有人认为
Some others think
你应该被破格提拔
that you should be promoted exceptionally
成为军中的精英
and make you an elite in the army.
我认为
I think
你有百分之五十的机会
you have 50% chance
会被赶出军队
to be kick out of the army,
我认为会有百分之五十的机会
I think I have 50% chance
留在军队
to stay in the army.
在我这没有那百分之五十
There is no other 50% in my case.
听说过战狼中队吗
Ever heard of wolf warrior detachment
听说过
Yes.
中国特种部队中的蓝军
It is the blue force in the Special Forces of PLA.
还有呢
And?
战狼中队
Walf warrior detachment
由中国特种部队中的精英组成
is formed by the elite of the PLA Special Forces.
装备最精良的武器
They are equipped with the best weapons,
模拟外军特种部队战术
simulate tactics of foreign special forces
不断挑战我军各精英部队
and constantly challenge our elite troops.
用尽方法
They do whatever they can
重创他们
to smash them
锤炼他们
and temper them.
特种部队中的特种部队
They are the special force in special forces.
报告
Report!
军中禁止饮酒
Drinking is not allowed in the army.
你现在还算是军人吗
Do you think you are still a soldier now?
喝了就能算吗
Am I if I drink?
也许
Maybe.
请问您是哪位
May I ask who you are?
我叫龙小云
I'm Long Xiaoyun,
现任战狼中队长
the current commander of Warwolf Company.
为什么当兵
Why choose the army?
当兵后侮两年
Choosing the army, I have regretted for two years,
不当兵后侮一辈子
but I would regret my whole life if I didn't.
真话
Truth?
Truth!
再喝
Drink more.
More.
您是想让我酒后吐真言
Are you trying to make me drunk and tell you the truth?
你会吐真言吗
Will you tell the truth?
会
Yes.
好
Good.
您想知道什么
What do you want to know?
我想看你喝醉酒什么样儿
I want to know what you will be like when you get drunk.
我从来没喝醉过
I've never been drunk.
我三岁开始喝酒
I started drinking when I was three.
五岁灌趴下两个比我大六岁的男生
At 5,made two boys six years older than me drunk before I do
十二岁酒壮怂人胆
At 12, I peeped at girls in showers
偷看女生洗澡
with some Dutch courage.
十七岁
At 17,
十七岁怎么了
What happened when you were 17?
你爸不管你吗
Has your father disciplined you?
在我出生之前
Before I was born,
爸爸就搬离了我们现在的家
my father left our current home.
妈妈想要孩子了
My mum wanted a baby,
就叫爸爸到家里来
so she invited my father over
请爸爸喝酒
for a drink.
爸爸喝醉了
Dad got drunk,
就有了现在的我
and here I am.
你们不许笑
Stop laughing-
冷锋你怎么又打人了
Leng Feng, How could you fight with others again?
排长
Platoon Commander,
带情报先走
take the intelligence and go.
不要再过来了
Don't come over any more.
排长
Platoon Commander,
快把情报送回去
send the intelligence back!
排长
Platoon Commander.
帮弟弟一个忙
Do your brother a favour.
给我个痛快吧
Make it quick.
给我来一枪吧
Shoot me.
这小子可是个刺头啊
That is a tough one.
战狼都是刺头
Everyone in Wolf detachment is tough.
不是刺头我们还不要呢
We don't want weak ones.
那好
Well.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
明天见 老师傅
See you, Sir.
啊
Ar!
我叫邵兵
My name is Shao Bing,
战狼的副队长
the Deputy Commander of Wolf Warrior detahment.
副队长好
My honor to see you, sir.
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
知道我们为什么叫战狼吗
Do you know why we are called Wolf warrior?
狼
Wolves
群体动物
are social animals.
一头狼
One wolf
打不过一头狮子或一头老虎
cannot defeat a lion or a tiger,
可是一群狼
but a wolf pack
可以天下无敌
can be invincible.
要团队合作
We need teamwork
而不是一个人逞英雄
not lone wolf.
炫耀个人能力
Or showing off individual abilities.
是
Yes, sir.
说到个人能力
Speaking of individual abilities,
我的队长告诉我
my commander told me
她发现了一个非常优秀的狙击手
that she found a marvelous sniper,
可是我真没看出来
but I really can't see
你有什么优秀
what so marvelous about you.
那您看出什么了
What have you seen?
如果这是战场
If we were on the battlefield,
你已经身陷重围了
you would have been surrounded.
连这点警觉性都没有
If you don't have such alertness,
你还当什么狙击手
how can you be a sniper?
如果这是真正的战场
If this is the real battlefield,
临死之前你最后的遗言是什么
what would be your last words?
报告
Sir!
没有那个时候
That won't happened to me.
理由
Why?
无障碍开阔隔离带
Here is a barrier-free open isolation zone,
装甲车
with armoured cars and
坦克
tanks.
如果这种防御
With such a defence,
还能让敌方几十名特种兵
if dozens of special soldiers from the enemy
成功挖掘战壕隐藏
could have successfully dug trenches and conceal themselves,
而我又正好在
and I just landed
敌方预伏陷阱正中心降落
in the middle of the enemy's ambush trap,
只有一个理由
there could only be one reason,
您带着所有部下一起叛国了
which is you have committed treason with all your men.
对待叛国者
To traitors,
我们通常会问候他的祖宗十八代
we usually damn all their ancestors.
是个刺头
This is a tough one,
像我们战狼
like our style.
这个距离
So close to his face,
不是打起来就是要接吻
they either begin to flight or begin to kiss.
有话您直说
What do you want to say,sir?
俞飞
Yu Fei.
到
Yes, sir.
他是你的了
He is all yours now.
是
Yes, Sir.
我是你分队长
I'm your Squad Commander.
我叫俞飞
My name is Yu Fei.
分队长好
Hello, Commander.
俺喜欢你
I like you.
欢迎来到战狼
Welcome to Wolves.
咋样
How is this?
战狼的欢迎仪式
The welcome ceremony into Wolves.
牛B吧
Is awesome, isn't it?
知道为啥吗
Do you know why?
为啥
Why?
老子天下第一
We are the fucking best.
告诉新来的
Tell this new guy
俺们中队的座右铭是啥啊
what the motto of our detachment is
谦虚
Be humble!
真没觉得
I really didn't see.
现在的情况怎么样
How is everything going now?
一切正常
All goes well.
老石
SN ,
把自己的作战指挥室
you gave up your operation room
交给龙小云那个丫头
to that girl, Long Xiaoyun
带着我们坐在指挥车里满山的跑
and running around with us in the van.
老石
SN ,
您辛苦啦
you have been working hard.
已经有四个老伙计
Four old fellows
被她奇袭斩首了
have been knocked out by her raid.
我不想成为第五个
I don't want to be the fifth.
我先让自己的指挥部移动起来
I need to make my headquarters mobile.
我倒要看看
I want to see
蛇没了七寸
that there is no Achilles heel,
她龙小云怎么一招制敌
how Long Xiaoyun can make her deadly blow.
冷锋
Leng Feng,
讲讲你三枪的故事吧
tell us your three-shoots story.
说话要谨慎啊
Be careful with your words.
死三八什么事都有你
Shit Rubberneck, you just can't leave things alone.
是史三八不是死三八
I'm Shi Rubberneck, not Shit Rubberneck.
这个二愣子
That idiot,
刚到战狼的第一天
on the very first day he came
就当众质问
Questioned in front of everyone
这么剽悍的部队
"Why is such a tough troop"
怎么队长是一个娘儿们
"led by a broad?"
后来被整了十七八次
He had been tricked for more than 17 times,
老实了
then he behaved.
说话小心点
Be careful with your words.
龙队是女的
Commander Long is a woman.
女的就是娘儿们
A woman is a broad.
我没说错吧
Am I wrong?
女人怎么了
What's the big deal being?
女人就不能当队长了啊
Can't a woman be a commander?
要我说啊
In my opinion,
没有龙队就没有咱们战狼
there will be no wolves without Commander Long,
是不是
right?
没错
Yes,
三八说得对
Rubberneck is right.
哎
Eh?
你应该领教过的
You should have already been taught a lesson.
要我说啊
In my opinion,
这种女人
what this kind of woman needs
就缺被男人征服
is to be conquered by a man.
被什么样的男人征服啊
By which kind of man?
就缺我这样的男人征服
A man like me.
怎么征服
How?
啊啊
Ah, ah!
报告
Ma'am
有防空武器拦截
We are running into anti-aircraft fire.
返航
Return to base!
投放诱饵
Drop the bait.
跳伞
Parachute.
开伞高度三百米
Opening altitude 300 metres.
注意安全
Be careful.
新丁加入
New man just joined in.
尽快磨合
Run him in as soon as possible.
是
Yes, Ma'am.
报告
Sir!
发现敌伞兵大规模空投
Find massive air-drop of enemy paratroopers.
首长
Commander,
这可是二战期问
this is a tactic used by large formations
大兵团作战才使用的战术啊
during World War ll.
这明显是个诱饵啊
They are obviously bait.
如果伞下面挂的是高爆炸弹
If there are high-explosive bombs
落在我们阵地上
and drop on our position,
我们就会伤亡惨重
we will have serious casualties.
一旦命令开火
If we fire back,
我们的防空火力就全暴露了
our anti-aircraft fire will be exposed.
统统暴露给他们
Then expose all to them.
命令地面防空部队
Command the anti-aircraft force
全面开火
to fire all weapons.
是
Yes, Sir.
报告
Sir!
夺取蓝方指挥许可权
We got the command authority of the blue force.
报告
Ma'am
红军已经侵入了
The red force has penetrated
我军的作战指挥系统
our operational command system.
还有呢
And?
我们已经失去了
We have lost
对作战部队的指挥权
the command authority to the combat troops.
问问炮团什么情况
Contact the artillery regiment now.
是
Yes, Sir.
先别打
Wait.
龙小云趁着我们侵入指挥系统
When we were trying to penetrate the system,
敌我双方
and set up a temporary virtual communication
临时建立虚拟通讯线路时
with the enemy,
用相同方式
Long Xiaoyun used the same method
向炮团发送了作战指令
and sent commands to the artillery regiment.
我们的一个机械化步兵团
One of our mechanised infantry regiments
已经被自己的炮团歼灭了
has been destroyed by our own artillery regiment.
有点意思
Interesting.
云姐
Yun,
干得漂亮
well done.
更有意思的是
What's more interesting is that
这个丫头还往我们的指挥系统里
this girl also has installed a virus
植入了一个病毒
in our operational command system.
如果刚才那个电话打出去
If we made the call just now,
不出三分钟
we would be bombed
炮弹就砸到这了
within three minutes.
好戏才刚刚开始
The game has just begun
老石
SN ,
你现在可以直接指挥蓝军了
you can directly command the blue force now.
模仿外军特种部队的作战方式
Copy the operation mode of foreign special forces.
我这二十年
I have been studying how to deal with foreign forces
研究的就是如何对付外军
for the last twenty years.
报告
Ma'am
发现团一级作战单位
Find a military unit the same size as a regiment.
报告
Ma'am
又发现两个团一级作战单位
Find another two military units the same size as regiments.
假的
Fake.
报告
Ma'am
和副队长他们之间不能取得联系
We lost contact with the Deputy Commander.
龙队
Commander Long,
听到请回答
please reply if you hear this.
这个太假了吧
It looks really fake.
对方就是让我们认为这是假的
They want us to think this is a fake one,
才会把真的放在这
so they left the real one here.
搞一下不就知道了吗
Let's check it out.
所有人注意
Attention,all units
动作一定要快
Move fast.
完成任务后
When your missions is done,
到指定地点集合
muster at the assigned place.
是
Yes, Sir.
等等
Wait.
如果他们就是想让我们以为
What if they want us to think
他们会把真的放在假的里面呢
they would put the real one in the fake one?
你这是在怀疑龙队的指令
Are you doubting Commander Long's order?
我了解红军指挥官
I know the red force's commander.
我觉得九成是陷阱
I think it's probably a trap.
执行命令
Follow the orders.
哎
Eh,
如果这真是假的
if this is a fake one,
战狼就输了
The wolf will be lost.
战狼就没输过
The wolf never loses.
我才刚开始喜欢你
I had just begun to like you,
现在我对你很失望
but now I'm really disappointed with you.
服从命令
Follow the orders,
士兵
soldier.
冷锋刚从红军那边过来
Leng Feng has just come over from the red force.
对他们的作战风格
He must be more familiar with the way they fight
肯定比咱们了解
than us.
要不我带着冷锋和三八
Shall I take Leng Feng and Rubberneck
在周边策应一下
and support from the perimeter?
嗯
Eh.
演习结束后
When the exercise finishes,
离开战狼吧
you better leave the Wolf.
完了 完了
We are so over.
我就说是假的吧
I told you it's fake.
装甲车
Armoured cars,
坦克
tanks.
我方几十名特种兵
Dozens of soldiers from our special force
成功进入
have successfully sneaked
敌方预伏陷阱正中心
into the center of enemy's ambush trap.
邵队
Commander Shao,
你带着部下集体殉国了
you are taking your men to die for our country together
这小子不错啊
He is good.
想办法把他挖过来
Make him one of us.
他是战狼中队的副队长
He is the Deputy Commander of Wolf warrior detachment
你一定把他给我整回来
You must get him for me.
把探路鸟收回来
Withdraw the exploring birds.
是
Yes, Sir.
就算咱仨现在冲下去
We won't be a thing to them
那也不够他们塞牙缝的
even if we rush down now.
战狼这次真的输了
It seems like the wolf will lose this time.
次那（俚语）
Shit.
这个不会也是假的吧
Is this a fake one too?
搞一下不就知道了
Let's check it out.
三
Three,
二
two,
一
0H6.
到
Arrive.
走光了
All gone.
注意警戒
Keep watching.
旅长
Brigade Commander,
您好
Hello, Sir.
旅长
Brigade Commander.
别问我
Don't ask me.
我已经阵亡了
I'm already dead.
报告
Report!
演习导演室判定
The exercise umpire team has judged
红军指挥官
that the red force's commander
被我军狙击手当场击毙
has been shot to death by our sniper.
李治军
Li Zhijun.
到
Yes, sir.
把人掏出来
Find them out.
是
Yes, Sir.
警卫连跟我走
Guard Company, follow me.
是
Yes, Sir.
打开视频
Switch on the video.
切断通话
Cut off the line.
我要让龙小云看着
I want Long Xiaoyun to see
她的手下一个个消失
her men disappear one by one.
是
Yes, Sir.
报告
Report!
作战部队通讯视频已恢复
The video communication with the operating force is back on,
但无法发送作战指令
but cannot send instructions.
冷锋同志
Leng Feng,
我来探访一下你
let me interview you.
把自己的老领导打败是什么感觉
What did you feel when you defeated your old commander?
以后你会不会也这么对我们啊
Will you do the same thing to us?
老首长说
The old commander said
演习就是实战
exercises are actual combats.
哎唷
Yo,
说实话
tell the truth,
这次真没人听得见
No one is listening now.
我们不会再害你了
We won't trick you again.
演习就是实战
Exercises are actual combats.
屁的
Bull Shit.
实战打的都是空包弹
Do actual combats fire empty bombs?
我来当兵就是为了打仗
The reason I joined the army is to fight,
现在呢
What
打来打去的
we fight over and over,
跟打过家家似的
as through we are playing a game.
打啥仗啊打仗
Why fight?
在家多陪陪老婆孩子多好啊
Nothing is better than staying with family at home.
我闺女
This is my little princess.
漂亮吧
Beautiful?
又把我未婚妻照片
Not again. Don't show my fiancme's photo
随便给别人乱看
to others.
我闺女才两岁
My girl is only two.
你都不放过
Leave her alone.
叫爹吧
Call me dad.
爹
Dad.
小兔崽子
You little bastard.
是邵队
Commander Shao is coming.
哈情况
What's happened?
狼
Wolves,
狼来了
wolves are coming.
其他人呢
Where are the others?
全部阵亡
All dead.
哎唷
Yo,
不就是几只狼吗
it's just a few wolves.
联络最近的直升机
Call the nearest helicopter.
直升机都归红军调配
All the helicopters are controlled by the red force.
我军正和红军处于交战状态
Our force is engaging with the red force.
立刻通过公共频道
Use the public channel
联络红军指挥官
to call the red force's commander immediately.
战备直升机已经起飞
Combat-ready helicopters have taken off
三十分钟左右到达
and will arrive within thirty minutes.
李治军 李治军
Li Zhijun. Li Zhijun.
马上增援战狼中队
Support the wolf detachment immediately.
他们遇到大麻烦了
They are in big trouble.
准备战斗
Ready to fight.
上刺刀
Fix bayonets.
听着
Listen up,
我们发现了目标
We found the target.
耶
Yeah.
但是他周围
However, he is surrounded
有一个师的中国解放军
by the entire army of the PLA.
战狼士兵个个要老婆
Every Wolf warrior wants a wife,
你要我要没有那么多
but we don't have enough girls.
遵守纪律能娶龙小云
You can get a Long Xiaoyun with discipline.
调皮捣蛋发个石青松
You can have a Shi Qingsong with misbehare.
指挥官都被击毙了
Their commander has been shot to death.
还追啊
Why are they still chasing us?
这不是玩赖吗
Is it fair?
这不公报私仇吗
Isn't it a revenge for personal reasons?
不行我要向领导汇报
That's not right. I'm going to report this to the officer.
刚离开原部队
You shot your old commander
就将老首长一枪击毙
right after you left your old troop.
我要是你连长
If I were your Company Commander,
我得弄死你
I would kill you.
老首长说
The old commander said
演习就是实战
exercises are actual combats.
锋子
Fe?g,
你小子太坏了
you bad ass.
哥几个
Guys,
还是快点走吧
Let's move faster.
我还是感觉不太对劲
I feel strange.
我们连长下手可黑啊
My old Company Commander is really black handed.
大家注意
Watch out!
有实弹
Live shell!
这不是演习
This is not an exercise.
马上联络指挥部
Call the headquarters.
站住
Freeze.
命令部队
Inform the force
进入战备状态
to be at combat readiness.
有外军入境
Foreign force crossed the border.
请求武装直升机
Request for armed helicopters.
载弹支援
Live shell support needed.
退后
Fall back.
他们的支援来了
Their reinforcement is coming.
我闺女
My little princess.
漂亮吧
Beautiful?
他们回来了
They are back.
快上来 咱们走
Mount up. Let's roll.
那么
So
他怎么样
How was he?
他跟他的武器一样烂
He's as faulty as his weapon.
哈 哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha ha
这太简单了
That was easy.
我觉得他们的地沟油
I'm sure their sewer will kill me
会比他们的士兵先杀掉我
before they actually do.
不要低估他们
Do not underestimate them.
记住 他们并没有实弹
Remember, they are unarmed.
就是简单的围剿一个人
A simple snatch and grab, man.
你应该当时就杀了他
You should've just killed him.
现在我们捅了马蜂窝
Now we just kicked the hornets' nest.
这正是我想要的
Exactly what I want it.
猴子 撒退计画怎么样了
Monkey, How is E&E looking?
一切尽在计画中 老大
Everything is good to go, man.
报告一号
Report to No. 1.
山鹰发现目标
Eagle spots the target.
这里是中华人民共和国领土
This is the territory of the People's Republic of China.
你们已经非法入侵
You are trespassing.
命令你们
I am ordering you
立刻停车
stop the vehicle
马上投降
and surrender immediately.
看来他们动真格的了
Things about to get real.
这也是你的计画吗
Is this a part of your plan, too?
先生们
Gentlemen,
表演即将开始
the show is about to begin.
有点意思
That was interesting.
快撤 快撒
Let's go. Let's go.
这里是中华人民共和国领土
You have invaded the territory
你们已经非法入侵
of the People's Republic of China.
我命令你们立刻停车 马上投降
Stop the vehicle and give up resistance
这里是中华人民共和国领土
This is the territory of the People's Republic of China.
你们已经非法入侵
You are trespassing.
命令你们
I am ordering you
立刻停车 马上投降
stop the vehicle and give up resistance.
这是最后警告
This is your last warning.
最后警告
Last warning.
撒
Move.
快走 快走
Let's move. Let's move.
报告机内设备仪表
Report! All the devices and instruments in the helicopter
全部失灵 全部失灵
are down, all down.
这是一场由境外雇佣军发起的
This is a well-plotted and targeted armed invasion
有目的有计划的武装入侵
started by foreign mercenaries.
上级命令我们
We are commanded
停止演习转为实战
to stop the exercise and turn to actual combat,
配合武警部队
co-operating with the armed police force
全面封锁边境
to completely block the border.
龙小云同志
Comrade Long Xiaoyun,
你参与这次作战行动的指挥
you are taking a part of this mission.
是
Yes, Sir.
我们截获了一段卫星电话通讯
We captured a piece of a call from a satellite phone
已经证实有外籍雇佣兵入境
proves that foreign mercenaries have invaded.
而且幕后的策划者很可能是
The mastermind behind is very likely
一个叫敏登的国际掮客
to be an international broker called Min Deng.
敏登
Min Deng.
他是被冷锋击毙的
He is the brother of Wu Ji,
武吉的哥哥
who was shot to death by Leng Feng.
奇怪的是
What's strange is
根据当时截获的信号
according to the signal we captured,
他已经入境了
he has already crossed the border
而且就在边境附近
and was not far from the border.
老猫呢
Where is Tomcat?
他人呢
Where is he?
老猫忙着呢
Tomcat is busy.
不是说这次行动他亲自押运吗
I was told he would be the escort himself in this mission.
他忙什么呢
What is he doing?
老猫忙着和老鼠
Tomcat is busy getting to know
相互了解呢
each other with the mouse.
老猫
Tomcat,
前海豹突击队队员
Former Seal member.
参加过两次海湾战争阿富汗战争
He has been in the Gulf War and in Afghanistan twice.
退役了之后
After his retirement,
加入了国际雇佣军组织
he has joint in an international mercenary organisation
目前是身价最高的
and is the most expensive one at the moment.
也从未失手过
He never failed before.
他的手下
All his members are also retired soldies
也都是来自各国特种部队的老兵
from special forces of different countries.
"Chinese Boy Scouts"
敏登派这么精锐的雇佣兵来
Min Deng sent such elite mercenaries here
就是为了给他弟弟报仇
just because he wants to revenge his brother,
就是为了来抓一个中国士兵
just because he wants a Chinese soldier.
敏登是个商人
Min Deng is a businessman.
他亲自入境
He came across the border himself
和老猫同时出现
and show up at the same time with Tomcat.
事情不是想象的那么简单
This is not as simple as that.
快 快 快
Hurry up!
快 快
Faster Move
担架
Stretcher
快
Move
来 小心点 小心点
Be careful
快 快 快
More careful
报告
Report!
这是飞行员冒死抢救回来的电板
This is a circuit board that the plot risked his life for.
石墨粉
Graphite powder.
他们在火箭弹里
They added massive amounts of graphite powder
添加了大量的石墨粉
into the rocket bomb.
这种东西只有千分之一毫米
This kind of thing is only a thousandth of a millimetre big.
一旦爆炸
Once the bomb explodes,
就会进入电子仪器
the powder will get into the electric instruments.
造成短路
And make them short circuit,
甚至电弧燃烧
even cause arc burning.
短时问内在空气中不会消失
It won't be disappeared in the air in a short time,
飞机无法进入
so aircraft cannot enter the area.
通知相关单位
Notify the relevant department.
对丛林
Make artificial rain
实施人工降雨
in the forest.
一个小时内
Use heavy rain
用大雨把石墨粉
to wash out all the graphite powder
通通冲刷干净
within one hour.
是
Yes, Sir.
我们分析
As we surmised,
老猫杀害了我方士兵
Tomcat killed one of our soldiers.
应该知道我们会封锁边境
He should know that we are going to block the border,
所以他现在逃离的路线
so the only way he could escape
只有这一条
is just this one.
这片丛林是以前战争遗留下来的雷区
This forest was a mine field in former battles,
这里遍布着大量的地雷
and is still covered with landmines,
未爆炸弹和防伞兵倒刺钩
unexploded ordnance and anti-paratrooper hooks.
为避免我方人员伤亡
To avoid casualties from our side,
我建议使用覆盖式轰炸
I suggest that we use carpet bombing.
同志们
Comrades,
看着你眼前牺牲的战友
look at the comrade who died in front of you
告诉我
and tell me,
这是什么
what is this?
这是战书
This is a letter of challenge.
是向中国军人的挑衅
The provocation to Chinese soldiers
再过六个小时
Six hours later,
敌人可能会穿越国境线
the enemies will possibly cross the border
逃出中国
and escape from China.
现在我命令你们
Now, I am giving you the order
把失去的尊严夺回来
to take our lost honour back.
如果在这个时间里
If you cannot complete your mission
你们没有完成任务
within the time,
我会调动战机
I will call for air support
对这片区域进行覆盖式轰炸
and carpet bomb the whole area.
我们将要守护的这个地方
The place we are going to protect
终年荒无人烟
is always desolate and uninhabited.
如果没有发生这场战斗
If this battle had not happened,
我们可能一辈子不会来到这里
we might never come here in our life.
这里没有青山绿水
There is no pretty views here,
没有金银宝藏
and there is no treasures here,
可是在我们军人的眼里
but in our soldiers' eyes,
这里是最美的地方
here is the most beautiful place,
因为它是中华人民共和国的国境线
because it is the border of the People's Republic of China,
是我们必须用生命和鲜血
It is the place that we must fight for
誓死捍卫的地方
with our lives and blood.
现在
Now,
让我们以军人的尊严宣誓
let's make a vow for the honour of our soldiers.
犯我中华者
Those who challenge China's resolve
虽远必诛
will have no safe place to hide
敬礼
Salute!
三队
Spread into three teams,
A组火力压制
Alpha, hold one
B组间接撒退
Bravo, bound back.
停
Stop!
有雷区
Mine field.
撒
Back off.
转移路线
Change route.
找到他们的头了吗
You got eyes on the brass?
放倒他
Put him down,
但不要杀了他
just wound him.
敌方有狙击手
They have snipers.
火力压制
Fire suppression.
卧倒
Lie down.
1点钟方向
One o'clock.
敌不在火力范围之内
The enemy is out of fire range.
狙击手
Sniper.
我们的狙击手在哪里
Where is our sniper?
到
Here.
回来
Come back.
不要再过来啦
Don't come again.
这是命令
This is the order.
队长 不要啊 队长
Commander, no! Commander.
连长 不要
Company commander. No.
Company commander, no!
你们干什么
What are you doing?
谁让你们冲上来的
Who told you to come over?
我的命令你们没听见吗
Haven't you heard my order?
都别上来啦
Stop coming.
听见了没有
Have you heard me?
兄弟们
Brothers.
求你们件事
I beg you.
帮哥哥一个忙
Do your brother a favour.
给我个痛快
Make it quick.
排长
Platoon Commander.
帮弟弟一个忙
Help your little brother.
求你了
Please.
给我个痛快吧
Make it quick.
给我来一枪吧
Shoot me.
谢谢
Thank you.
停
Stop!
冷锋
Leng Feng,
你
You.
等你能活着回来再关我禁闭吧
Confine me if you can come back alive.
他怎么样
How about him?
死不了
Won't die.
他交给我你们继续迂回追击
Continue to outflank I will take care him.
他要干什么
What is he doing?
一名资深狙击手最快需要2.5秒
A good sniper need 2.5 seconds at least.
我2.3秒
Only 2.3 seconds for me.
你确定要这么做吗
Are you sure you are going to do this?
报告
Report!
请求行动
Action request!
行动
Action!
转移到制高点
Change position. Move to high ground.
走
Go!
目标在十点钟方向速度很快
Target, ten o'clock, moving fast.
干掉他
Take him!
干掉他 现在
Take him out! now.
到
Arrived.
冷锋
Leng Feng,
你没事吧
Are you OK?
妈的
Fuck
不打头
Missed my head
打老子衣服
Shot my clothes.
到
Arrived.
哎
Ar.
你喝醉了啥样
What do you look like when you are drunk?
那你得先活着回来
Come back alive first
糟了
Shit!
走
Go!
快走
Move!
死三八
Shit Rubberneck!
你不会真的死了吧
Are you really dead?
醒醒啊
Wake up!
死三八
Rubberneck!
没死也被你摇死了
I will be dead if you keep shaking.
谁叫你枪法那么烂的
Blame your rubbish marksmanship.
疼 疼
It hurts. It hurts.
你不疼吗
Don't you feel hurt?
我忍着
I can hold.
警方传来敏登的照片
Police sent photos of Min Deng.
当时他正在
He was meeting with
和某生物制药机构负责人碰头
the head of a bio-pharmaceutical company.
生物制药
Bio-pharmaceutical?
一个月前
One month ago,
我们一家中老年疾病预防中心
one of our disease prevention and control centres
被商业间谍侵入
was broken by commercial spies.
成功的窃取了
They successfully stole
海量的志愿者血液样本
a huge number of blood samples of volunteers,
和变异病毒的基因资料
and genetic data of variant viruses.
如果这些样本和资料
If these samples and data
落到了所谓的
finished up at this so called
这家国际生物制药公司的手里
international bio-pharmaceutical company,
那么他们就会根据中国人的基因
They would make disease with Chinese genes
制造出只在中国人之间传染的疾病
that can only infect Chinese people.
甚至可以让新生婴儿的畸形率
Or even increase the malformation rate of new-borns
达到万倍以上
by over ten thousand times.
基因武器
Genetic weapon.
这是老猫发来的
This is from Tomcat.
中国军队的边境布防图
The border deployment map of China Military.
他说边境已经全面封锁了
He said the border has been completely blocked,
让咱们把真正想办的事情
and let us think of a way out ourselves
自己想办法办了
to do what we really want to do.
冷锋踩得是82型防步兵地雷
This is the MD-82-B Antipersonnel Mine.
爆炸方向180
Burst direction 180,
扫射面积30立方米
explosion area 30 cubic metres,
杀伤力百分之九十八
probability of kill 98%,
地雷内部装有一百颗钢珠
with 100 steel shots inside the mine.
人工排雷的成功率极低
Successful manual disarming rate is very low.
地雷上方的压力变化
The changing pressure
不可以超过500克的范围
cannot exceed 0.5 kilograms
如果
if...
安静
Quiet!
冷锋
Leng Feng,
你听我说
Listen to me.
要小心
Be careful.
一定要小心
You must be very careful.
我等你回来请我喝酒
I'll wait for you back to buy me a drink.
冷锋 冷锋
Leng Feng, Leng Feng.
冷锋
Leng Feng.
回答我
Anwser me.
冷锋 你没事吧
Leng Feng, are you OK?
冷锋 冷锋
Leng Feng, Leng Feng.
耶
Yeah.
疼死我了
That's hurt.
龙小云
Long Xiaoyun,
你有男朋友吗
do you have a boyfriend?
他问你有没有男朋友
He is asking you if you have a boyfriend.
没有
No.
什么
What?
什么什么
What, what?
她说她没有
She said she doesn't have one.
死三八
Shit Rubberneck!
要不是你我早就干死那个大个子了
I would have long killed that big guy without you.
我叫史三八
I'm Shi Rubberneck,
不是死三八
Not Shit Rubberneck.
哎
Ar.
同志
Comrade,
一定要找到冷锋啊
you have to find Leng Feng.
放心吧
Don't worry.
我一定找到他
I Will find him.
站住
Freeze.
跟我玩腿是吧
Are you kicking legs with me?
我必须得承认
You know I'll go admit
你不是我见过最聪明的士兵
you may not be the smartest soldier I have ever seen, but
但你是最勇敢的
you are the bravest.
你丫会讲中文吗
Can you son of a bitch speak Chinese?
什么
What?
靠
Fuck!
你们说你们是雇佣兵的禁地
You call youself the mercenary red zone.
但你们其实只是一帮童子军
You are not but a bunch of boy scouts
告诉你
Listen,
你们丫到中国就别想出去
don't even think of going back when you break into China.
看看你自己
Look at you.
你想为你的国家而死
You are willing to die for your country,
但我告诉你 小子
but I got news for you, bucko.
这改变不了什么
Doesn't make a difference.
你知道我为什么而战吗
Wanna know what I fight for?
钞票
Money.
你妈的
You are fucking...
你会因为你的国家而死
You want to die for your country.
冷锋同志
Leng Feng,
一定要坚持住啊
Hold on.
杀
Kill!
来啊
Come.
Now what
来啊
What
带走
Take away.
美的地方都有故事
Every beautiful place has stories.
犯我中华者
Those who challenge China's resolve
虽远必诛
will have no safe place to hide.
这是冷锋让我交给您的
Leng Feng asked me to give you this.
他也遇到围尸打援
He met the same situation as you did.
他冲上去
He went ahead
救回了战友
and saved his comrade.
他让我告诉您
He wants me to tell you
冲上去被打死很容易
it is easy to get killed.
难的是背负着内疚和使命感
But living with
继续活下去
the guilt and the responsibility is hard.
排长
Platoon Commander,
求你个事
I beg you.
帮弟弟个忙
Do your brother a favour.
给我个痛快吧
Make it quick.
谢谢
Thanks.
首长辛苦了
Commander, hard work for you.
为人民服务啊
Serve the people.
我见过你爸了
I have met your father.
满意吗
Happy?
我老了比他还帅
I'll be more handsome when I get old.
你脚下的那颗雷是怎么排除的
How did you clear the mine you were on?
我有点一时想不起来了
I can't remember.
要不你再请我喝顿酒
How about you buy my some drink.
你等着关禁闭吧
Wait for your confinement.
"Chinese Boy Scouts"